Guide to the American Left Ephemera Collection, 1875-2015 AIS.2007.11
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Realia: Pins and Other Objects, XXIII.
  - "We're here for you, you're out there for us" Pin
  - "Register for Peace - Indianapolis, May 22" Pin
  - "Peace" Pin
  - "Vote Socialist Workers in '72 - Jennings and Pulley" Pin
  - "Vote Socialist Worker in '68" Pin
  - "Vote Communist - Mitchell and Zagarell" Pin
  - "No Nukes" Pin
  - "Vote Socialist Workers in '72 - Linda Jennings for Pres." Pin
  - "Vote Socialist Workers in '72 - Andrew Pulley for V.P." Pin
  - "Amter for Congress" Pin
  - "E.R.A. in '76! Vote Socialist Workers" Pin (Box 36, Item 1)
  - "Death to the Shah: U.S. Imperialism Get Your Bloody Hands Off Iran!" RCYB Pin (Box 36, Item 2)
  - "Work for a Non-Nuclear World" Pin (Box 36, Item 3)
  - "Stop! Nuclear power/Nuclear Weapons" (2) Pin (Box 36, Item 4)
  - "Neutralize the C.I.A." Pin (Box 36, Item 5)
  - "No Nukes Now!" Pin (Box 36, Item 6)
  - "YSA" Pin (Box 36, Item 7)
  - "Bring Yanks Home/ Yank the Cops from Harlem/Vote Socialist Workers" Pin (Box 36, Item 8)
  - "Don't Mourn- Organize" Pin (Box 36, Item 9)
  - "Solar Employs, Nuclear Destroys" Pin (Box 36, Item 10)
  - "Moratorium IV" Pin (Box 36, Item 11)
  - "Energy for People Not Profit" People's Power Coalition Pin (Box 36, Item 12)
  - "Bring Peace to Vietnam/ Support the National Liberation Front" Pin (Box 36, Item 13)
  - "Make Love Not War" Pin (Box 36, Item 14)
  - "Political Suspensions M.A.P.S." Pin (Box 36, Item 15)
  - "Pulley for Vice-President" Pin (Box 36, Item 16)
  - "Keep Biafra Alive" Pin (Box 36, Item 17)
  - "Peace on Earth Work for Peace" Pin (Box 36, Item 18)
  - "No Tuition Tax War Profits" Pin (Box 36, Item 19)
  - "Impeach Nixon" Pin (Box 36, Item 20)
  - "Kill for Peace/Kill for Freedom/ Kill Vietnamese/ Kill,Kill!" Pin (Box 36, Item 21)
  - "El Salvador is Spanish for Vietnam" Pin (Box 36, Item 22)
  - "We're in Here for You/ You're Out There for Us" Pin (Box 36, Item 23)
  - "Peace" Pin (Box 36, Item 24)
  - "Peace Now!" (Box 36, Item 25)
  - "Caution: Military Service May Be Hazardous to Your Health" Pin (Box 36, Item 26)
  - La Causa Pin, 1970 (Box 36, Item 27)
- Twenty-First Century Radical Movements, XXIV.
  This series includes an eclectic mixture of flyers and occasional pamphlets mostly what Oestreicher picked up from events he attended or witnessed in Pittsburgh and Taos, New Mexico. Many of the Pittsburgh materials come from student groups at the University of Pittsburgh, from the Pittsburgh Occupy movement, the Battle of Homestead Foundation (a group of aging New Left labor activists and academics), and demonstrators at the G-20 meetings held in Pittsburgh in 2009.
  Taos, New Mexico, where Oestreicher has a summer home, has long had a visible activist community. Since the early 1900s it attracted an artist's colony as well as other Avant-garde intellectuals like Mable Dodge Luhan and D.H. Lawrence. In the late 1960s a substantial cohort of hippie counterculturalists settled in the Taos area and many stayed after their communes fell apart. In recent years the activist community has also benefited from academic and professional retirees attracted by the area's culture and surroundings.
  - New Mexico, 1.
    - "In the Name of Sustainability" Taos Flyer, November 2013 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - "Food Activists Cited" Flyer. Taos, June 2013 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - "Night at the Puppetista", Taos Alehouse (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Taos Vegan Meetup, Double-sided flyer (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Pecha Kucha Night flyer. Taos (2 Copies) (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Freedom in Music Project fundraiser leaflet. Taos (2 Copies), August 2013 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Code Pink Flyers (2). Taos (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - "The Message of the Bulldozers". Taos, July 2008 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Taos World Peace Conference, May 2009 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Taos Peace House and Infoshop Volunteer Flyers (2) (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Global Peace Walk Brochure. Taos, 2012 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - "World Peace Week: Peace is Possible" Flyer. Taos (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Habitat for Humanity Affiliate Brochure, Taos (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Peaceful Skies Coalition Flyer (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - "Voices From the Land" Flyer for Sovereign Dineh Nation event (2 Copies) (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - "Stand Up!" Comment on the Supplemental Environmental Impact Statement, 2011 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - "Restore the Constitution" License Plate Civil Disobedience Flyer, (2 Copies), September 2013 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - "The Change We Knead Now" Bake Bread for World Peace, July 2009 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - News Articles Relating to Environmental Issues (3 pieces), 2013-2015 (Box 39, Folder 23)
    - Bernie Sanders New Mexico Flyers (3 pieces), 2016 (Box 39, Folder 24)
  - Pennsylvania, 2.
    - "Who Decides- Corporations, or 'We The People'?" Gas Extraction Flyer, 2011 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - Rally for a Responsible Budget Flyer (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - "In April We Take a Stand for Workers like Donnell Simmons" Clean Up Sodexo Flyer (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - Occupy: JP Morgan Flyer, 2011 (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - Occupy Chant Leaflet, 2011 (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - Fight Back America Flyer (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - Bring Them Home Now! Flyer, 2005 (Box 20, Folder 25)
    - Thank You Snowden Sticker (Box 20, Folder 26)
    - Rally For Single-Payer Healthcare, (3 items), October 2009 (Box 20, Folder 27)
    - "Why U.S. Workers Need a Labor Party" Pamphlet (Box 20, Folder 28)
    - "Dear Occupiers: A Letter from Anarchists", 2011 (Box 20, Folder 29)
    - Mumia Abu-Jamal items: 2 Pamphlets, 1 Petition, 2011 (Box 20, Folder 30)
    - Battle of Homestead Foundation Schedule of Pump House Events, April 2014 (Box 20, Folder 31)
    - Audit the Fed Flyer, February 2009 (Box 20, Folder 32)
    - $1,000,000 Bill: Biblical Outreach (Box 20, Folder 33)
    - No Bad Cops Leaflet (Box 20, Folder 34)
    - "Mobilization for Climate Justice", December 2009 (Box 20, Folder 35)
    - "Something is Terribly Wrong..." (Box 20, Folder 36A)
    - "Enough!!" (Box 20, Folder 36B)
    - Jill Stein 2016 Green Party Election Poster and Flyer (Box 39, Folder 22)
  - Pittsburgh, 3.
    - "1968: a Year in Revolt" University of Pittsburgh, April 2008 (Box 20, Folder 37)
    - "Pennsylvania is Going Green" Pamphlet (Box 20, Folder 38)
    - Celebration of the Lives of Dennis Brutus and Howard Zinn. University of Pittsburgh, April 2010 (Box 20, Folder 39)
    - "Marx in Soho" University of Pittsburgh, (2 Copies), February 2010 (Box 20, Folder 40)
    - Stop McCarthyism at Pitt! (Box 20, Folder 41)
    - "After Chavez: Where is the Venezuelan Revolution Going?" (Box 20, Folder 42)
    - Budget Cuts Rally Flyer, University of Pittsburgh, October 2011 (Box 20, Folder 43)
    - "Your Major Might Not Be Here Next Year" University of Pittsburgh, April 2011 (Box 20, Folder 44)
    - Mark Rudd Today. University of Pittsburgh, March 2010 (Box 20, Folder 45)
    - Indonesian Garment Workers Speak Out. University of Pittsburgh, February 2013 (Box 20, Folder 46)
    - Pittsburgh Thomas Merton Center: Small Anti-Iraq War card and donation letter (Box 20, Folder 47)
    - "All Power to the General Assemblies of Workers, Students, and Unemployed." Occupy (Box 20, Folder 48)
    - "What Happened on Friday Night?" University of Pittsburgh, September 2009 (Box 20, Folder 49)
    - The Peoples' March to the G-20, September 2009 (Box 20, Folder 50)
    - "Help Stop Coca-Cola's Worldwide Abuses!" (Box 20, Folder 51)
    - HELP: Stop Organ Harvesting in China (Box 20, Folder 52)
    - Pittsburgh Against Torture Postcard, September 2009 (Box 20, Folder 53)
    - ACLU: Know Your Rights, 2009 (Box 20, Folder 54)
    - Voice of Revolution. (2 Copies), September 2009 (Box 20, Folder 55)
    - Spartacist, Spring 2009 (Box 20, Folder 56)
    - Why We March and Occupy! Flyer, 2011 (Box 20, Folder 57)
    - "We Are One: Respect Our Rights" Flyer (2 Copies), April 2011 (Box 20, Folder 58)
    - Rally to Stop the Bus Cuts! Leaflet (Box 20, Folder 59)
    - "From Wall Street to Pittsburgh: We Need a Labor Party!", October 2011 (Box 20, Folder 60)
    - An Introduction to Socialism- Flyer (2 Copies) (Box 20, Folder 61)
    - "What is Marxism?" University of Pittsburgh (Box 20, Folder 62)
    - ICH Presents: Creative Justice (Box 20, Folder 63)
    - Nordenberg Sweatshop Flyer, University of Pittsburgh (Box 20, Folder 64)
    - Occupy Pittsburgh Now no.7 (2 Copies), September 2012 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Newspapers Collected from Pittsburgh G-20 Protests, 2009 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - The New People Magazine: Pittsburgh Thomas Merton Center. 3 issues, 1990-2012 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - "Rising Textbook Prices, Rising Capitalist Profits" Flyer, ca. 2012-2015 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - "Capitalisn abd Climaate Change: Which Way Forward?" Flyer (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - "Heni Sutisna + Aslam Hidayat: Indonesian Garment Workers Speak Out" Flyer (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - "Marxism and the Emancipation of Women" Flyer (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - "David Montgomery 1927-2011. A Pittsburgh Celebration of his Life" Program, February 11, 2012 (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - "The U.S. Working Class and the Crisis of World Capitalism" Flyer (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - "Socialism: What is it? And how?" Flyer (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - "Fight For $15! Fight For Socialism!" Flyer (Box 38, Folder 14)
    - "Pittsburgh Socialist Alternative: The Struggle For $15/Hour" Flyer, April - May 2015 (Box 38, Folder 15)
    - "Fight For $15 and a Union" Flyer (Box 38, Folder 16)
    - Homestead News BHF Schedule of Pump House Events, 2014 (Box 38, Folder 17)
    - Pittsburgh Students for Police Accountability Flyer (Box 38, Folder 18)
    - "Building Student Power" Flyer (Box 38, Folder 19)
    - "Walk Away From Your Syllabus" Packet (Box 38, Folder 20)
    - AFL-CIO Organizing Institute Flyer (Box 38, Folder 21)
    - "Could America Go Socialist? Bernie Sanders and the 2016 Election" Flyer (Box 38, Folder 22)
    - "The Promise of Anarchism: An International Panel Discussion" Flyer (Box 38, Folder 23)
    - Rainbow Alliance "Identities: The Acronym and Beyond" Flyer (Box 38, Folder 24)
    - "Strike" Fight For 15 Flyer (Box 38, Folder 25)
    - PGH Area Flyers (mostly recent, 19 pieces), 1980s-Present (Box 39, Folder 25)
    - Poster, Demo Against War in iraq (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Poster, Working Class Images (Box 40, Folder 4)
- Democratic Socialism, XXV.
  A faction within the Socialist Party USA, led by Michael Harrington, founded the Democratic Socialist Organizing Committee in 1973. It began with a few hundred members growing to perhaps 6,000 in 1982 when it merged with the New American Movement (a New Left holdover) and renamed itself the Democratic Socialists of America. Despite its small numbers, the organization had some prominence owing to Harrington's public persona as well the affiliation of such nationally visible politicians as Vermont's Senator Bernie Sanders, Detroit congressmen George Crockett and John Conyers, and California congressman Ron Dellums.
  - "What is Democratic Socialism" YDS, ca. 1990s (Box 22, Folder 31)
  - Steven Soifer, The socialist Mayor: Bernard Sanders in Burlington, Vermont, 1991 (Box 39, Folder 26)
  - Socialist Alternative Issues (2 issues), March 2016, July/August 2016 (Box 39, Folder 27)
- Food Not Bombs, XXVI.
  Founded by activists in Cambridge, Ma. In 1980, the organization claims more than 400 worldwide affiliates today. They feed vegetarian meals to the hungry and lobby and demonstrate peacefully against militarism and for changed government budget priorities. In recent years members have been harassed by local, state, and federal government authorities both because some local merchants and politicians fear that public visibility of the poor and homeless may drive away business and because elements in the national security state imagine that their antimilitarist agitation may constitute a national security threat. Food distributors have been arrested in several locales. Some activists have found their mail service interrupted and their bank accounts disrupted.
  - Military Spending Surge Flyer, ca. 2012 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Free Skool Welcome Day, 2013 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - "Solidarity Not Charity", Flyer. (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - "Food Not Bombs founder lives his philosophy" Flyer, 2011 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Sample Agenda for your First Meeting (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Free Skool Schedules Weeks 12-15, 2013 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Autoonomous Playhouse Comic Anthology #1 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Food Not Bombs Calling Card (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Free Meal Flyer (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Food Not Bombs Anniversary Gathering, May 2009 (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Food not Bombs Postcard Flyer, 2 (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - "Food is a Right, Not a Privilege" (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - "Cook For Peace" (2 Copies) (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - "A Dollar For Peace" Flyer (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - "What is Foreclosure?" (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - "Enjoy a Free Meal" (Box 23, Folder 25)
  - "Food Not Bombs: Ad Flyers, 2 Copies (Box 23, Folder 26)
  - Harvest Fest Flyer, September 2013 (Box 23, Folder 27)
  - "What's Wrong with McDonalds?" Flyer (2 Copies) (Box 23, Folder 28)
- Populists/Pre-Populists, XXVII.
  The term populist entered American political discourse with the appearance of the People's or Populist Party in 1892. Their presidential candidate, James Weaver, got 8.5% of the national popular vote, and the Party expanded that percentage in the 1894 congressional elections. Much of the Party supported the Democrat William Jennings Bryan in 1896 and the Party declined thereafter. Populists carried several states electing governors, senators and congressmen. They campaigned against banks, monopolies and railroads and for railroad and banking regulation, expansionary monetary policies, and framers' cooperatives. Initially drawing support mainly from wheat and cotton belt farmers, they also supported labor reforms and drew significant working –class support in 1894. A variety of organizations with similar programs and rhetoric had preceded the People's Party in the previous two decades and are also included here.
  - "Sovereigns of Industry" Addendum. E.M. Chamberlain, 1875 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Sovereigns of Industry Membership Card, 1874 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - "Up to Date: Coins Financial School Continued", WH Harvey, 1895 (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - "Coins Financial School" WH Harvey, 1894 (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - "Coin on Money, Trusts, and Imperialism" WH Harvey, 1899 (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Coxey His Own Story, April 1914 (Box 25, Folder 19)
- Radical Academics, XXVIII.
  The New Left was disproportionately a movement of University students. Many went on to graduate school and then became professors in various academic disciplines. In many of the academic professional organizations these New Leftists organized radical caucuses to lobby on issues like the Vietnam War or racism, sponsor sessions at national meetings, or issue their own publications. Left-wing economists, for example, organized the Union for Radical Political Economy (URPE) and published substantial newsletter. The Radical Historians Organization created a journal, the Radical History Review that is still published today.
  - Radical Historians Newsletter no. 76(2 Copies), June 1997 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Radical Historians Newsletter no. 38, November 1982 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Radical Teacher. 5 issues: 8-12, 1978-1979 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Radical Teacher. 5 issues: 15-21, ca. 1980s (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Radical Teacher. 4 issues: 23, 30, 34-35, ca. 1988 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Essays on the Social Relations of Work and Labor, A Special Issue of The Insurgent Sociologist, Fall 1978 (Box 38, Folder 26)
  - Pamphlet, Academic Freedom Be Damned, 1986 (Box 39, Folder 28)
  - URPE; The War and Its Impact on the Economy, 1970 (Box 39, Folder 29)
  - Yale Poster "Impeach the President!", 1973 (Box 40, Folder 5)